《越狱》第四季 第十集
Prison.Break.S04E10
《越狱》  前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break.
如果你们成功得到“锡拉”
If you're successful with obtaining Scylla,
不仅不用坐牢
you'll not only avoid jail time,
而且可以因为帮助国家
but you could take great pride in knowing
除去这个巨大的威胁  而得到奖励
you helped dismantle this country's greatest threat to its own democracy.
如果在执行任务中被杀
If you're killed while doing so,
将会得到体面的葬礼
a proper funeral will be provided.
格雷琴有其余的图纸
Gretchen has the rest of the pages.
除非她把几页纸给我们  否则就无法前进
We can't go any further until she gives them back.
为什么还要这么做
Why are we doing this again?
这是安全保障
It's an insurance policy.
你如果再用枪指着我
You put a gun on me again,
我就连你的指纹也一起取了
and these aren't the only set of prints I'll be copying.
迈克
Mike!
迈克尔  你怎么了  跟我说话  迈克尔
Michael, what's wrong? Talk to me! Michael?
我要"锡拉"明天之内移出
I want Syclla out of Los Angeles by the end of the day
洛城
tomorrow.
布拉德  快出来
Brad, get out of there!
-使劲推  -别这样做
Push it! Don't do this!
布拉德
Brad!
如果出现什么状况
If anything should happen,
给我芝加哥的妈妈打个电话
call my mom in Chicago.
不会有什么状况发生的
Nothing's going to happen.
布拉德的尸体在哪
Where's Brad's body now?
运往停尸房的路上 放在国土安全局的冷柜里
We got it on its way to the morgue, and it's in the cooler
没有人会发现的
at Homeland Security where nobody can find it.
这不是我们之前说好的
That ain't part of the deal.
你说过如果我们发生意外 我们会被送到家人手里
You said if anything happened to us,that we'd be returned to next of kin.
这不是我当时说的
That's not exactly what I said.
不  这就是你当时说的
No, that is exactly what you said.
我不是那么说的
No, it isn't exactly what I said, okay?
他现在是一具无名男尸  除非我说他不是
And he needs to stay a John Doe until I say otherwise.
我现在要处理的事情已经很多了
Okay? I'm dealing with enough stuff already
而且我的处境也不妙
and I've had my ass chewed out...
他有
He's got...
他还有妈妈  你知道吗
He's got a mother, you know.
如果你还想要"锡拉"
If you want Scylla, and I assume you still do,
就把布拉德・贝里克的尸体运回给他妈
Brad Bellick's body goes home to his mother.
好吧  好吧
All right, all right.
我去处理尸体的事
All right, I'm gonna take care of the body.
但是你们
But you guys
不能再伤感下去了
need to get out of mourning.
我们得马上回到工作上
Okay, we need to get back to work.
把布拉德的遗物收拾一下
You need to pack Brad's stuff up,
回到正常的工作上
and we need to get back to work.
还有  费尔南多
And Fernando,
朋友  我忠告你
my friend, let me tell you something.
如果你再碰我一下
If you ever put your hands on me again,
我保证
I promise you, okay,
我让你一起去陪葬
there's gonna be two bodies in the fridge.
我需要答案
But I need results.
我需要缺失的几页纸
Yeah, well, I need to see those missing pages.
你说呢
So, what's it gonna be?
我听说你死了
I heard you were dead.
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
一只小鸟
A little bird.
你怎么这么大方
That's awfully generous of you.
我要算准时机
It's all a matter of timing.
"公司"要把"锡拉"转移到滨洲的一个地堡里
The Company is moving Scylla to a bunker in Pennsylvania.
-什么时候  -明天
When? Tomorrow.
你在得知后  应该马上给我电话
You want to make sure to mention that on the phone right away, as soon as...?
说实话  作为前雇员
You know, for an ex-employee,
你对公司的现况应该了解很多
you sure seem to know an awful lot about current Company business.
别这么偏激
Don't get paranoid.
我不正在为你们打探消息嘛
I'm keeping one ear to the ground for your benefit,
所以  你们最好跟我合作  而不是针对我
which is a really good reason to work with me and not against me.
好了  我们拿到图纸了
All right, you know what? We got our pages.
走吧
Let's go.
那是运输部的安泽
That's Enzen from transpo.
他负责电力传输
He's responsible for the power transfer.
鲍威尔  你认识的
And you know Powell.
他监管安全装置
He's supervising the security override.
这是个大工程
It's a big job.
也许我们应该找大卫・贝克
Perhaps we should call in David Baker.
确保安全
Just to be safe.
没必要
That won't be necessary.
我们内部的人就可以完成
We can do this all in-house, huh?
"锡拉"明天就不在这了
And Scylla will be gone by morning.
我答应过布拉德  发生意外就打电话给他妈
I promised Brad I would call his mom if anything happened.
需要的话 我帮你打
I'll do it if you want.
没关系  我来打
No, it's okay. I'll do it.
看看这个
Look at this.
警察慈善会时  他留了个徽章
He kept a badge from the police benefit.
他在福克斯河监狱当狱警时
When he was a CO in Fox River,
他考了5次警官学院  都没有通过测试
he-he failed the test to get into the academy five times.
图是真的吧
These are right, right?
这是"公司"地下室的地图  对吧
This is a map of the Company's basement, right?
我不明白  看起来太简单了
I don't know. It looks too simple.
我以为会更复杂一点
I assumed it would be a lot more complicated than this.
这些符号是
These symbols-- they're...
根本没有意义  还有这些字母
They don't make any sense, and the letters, uh...
肯定有什么地方错了
There's just something wrong.
字母C
This letter C--
一般表示散热口
it usually designates some kind of heating vent.
M表示计量器
The M designates a meter.
这是某种冷凝装置
This is some sort of condensing unit.
这是管道设备  叫做P型管
This is a plumbing part. It's called a P-trap.
他们是完全不同的东西
They're all completely dissimilar items.
设计逻辑学里  这些
Logical design dictates they'd never
不能随意安装
be installed that randomly.
根本
It just, um...
一点意义都没有
It doesn't make sense.
C  M  E
C
M
E
C  M  E
是"看我"
That's "See me."
如果把这些字母当符号
These letters don't make any sense
一点意义都没有
if you think of them as symbols,
但从字面意思来看  就有意义了
but they do if you think of them literally.
"你看到我了吗"  他是在问
"Do you see me?" He's asking
如果你看到了
if you see him.
在哪
Where?
在这
Here.
大卫・贝克
David Baker?
但除了你们俩  谁能想到
Yeah, but who besides you two, would come up
这样的点子呢
with something like that, huh?
什么意思呢
I mean, what's the point?
我不知道
I don't know,
如果不找出画这张蓝图的人
but we're never going to figure this blueprint out
我们永远不知道其中的意义
if we can't find the person who drew it.
我们要找出大卫・贝克
We need David Baker.
你好  亲爱的
Hello, darling.
早上好
Good morning.
你的咖啡  一勺糖  两勺奶
Here is your coffee, one sugar, two creams.
这是你要的指纹
And those fingerprints you ordered.
格雷琴的吗
Gretchen's?
是的  格雷琴・路易斯・摩根
Yes. Gretchen Louise Morgan.
你怎么会得到这些东西
How did you pull off a thing like that?
我有个朋友在捷普科技工作
I have a friend who works with the CHIPS.
不过别太高兴  没多大收获
But don't get too excited. There's not much there.
格雷琴・路易斯・摩根
Gretchen Louise Morgan.
出生日期  77年3月29日  生于西佛州的约翰斯敦
DOB: 3-29-77, Johnstown, West Virginia.
姐姐住在里弗赛德
Her sister lives in Riverside.
父亲已故
Daddy deceased.
得过马术奖
Award-winning equestrian.
伊拉克战争队伍军人
Iraqi war vet.
-不是吧  -没有前科
I'll be damned. Clean-cut chick.
至少档案上没有
At least on paper.
我看不出她和
But I don't see any evidence
中国犯罪集团有什么联系
that she's related to Chinese organized crime.
老公不在北京
No husband in Beijing?
没有敲诈勒索犯罪记录
No prior arrest for extortion?
没有
Nope.
-没有任何跟我们认识的人有关的吗  -我查了
No mention of any of our friends? Hmm. I checked.
没有提到斯科菲尔德  布伦斯  惠斯勒
No Scofield, no Burrows, no Whistler.
惠斯勒
Whistler?
你怎么知道这个名字
How do you know that name?
詹姆斯・惠斯勒
James Whistler?
我听到斯科菲尔德有天提起过他
I heard Scofield mention him one day.
哪天
What day?
我见到他的那天
The day that I met him.
哪句话说的
In what context?
我不记得了
I-I don't remember.
怎么了  有什么问题吗
Why? What's the big deal?
他是谁
Who is he?
谁也不是
Nobody.
就先这样吧
That will be all for now.
这还有一个  大卫・艾伦・贝克
Here's another one-- David Allen Baker.
他是城市规划委员会的一名顾问
He's an advisor to the city planning commission.
他设计的低收入住房还得过奖
Won an award for designing low-income housing.
妻子叫伊莱恩
Wife is named Elaine, and there's
这是他的住址
the address.
我打印一份地图
I'll print a map.
我们还需要
All right, we still
第六张卡  对吧
need that sixth card, all right?
是吗
Really?
好了
All right.
穿过主水管道之后
We've got at least 30 more yards to go
还有30码才能到达"公司"大楼
past the water main before we get to the Company building.
迈克尔  看到这个吗
Michael, Michael, see that?
这看起来
That looks like it could be
像是隧道里的障碍物
some sort of obstruction in the tunnel.
不管是什么  无论如何
Whatever it is, whatever it takes,
我们要在接下来几个小时内穿过去
we got to get through that in the next few hours.
我要你们先去那儿着手准备
I want you guys to go down there and get started.
我和莎拉去找大卫・贝克
Sara and I will go and look for, uh... for David Baker.
然后送贝里克回他妈妈那
And Bellick gets back to his mom.
对  一旦我们拿到"锡拉"
Yeah, and when we get Scylla,
我们就摆脱这一切
we're walking away from this crap.
完全正确
Absolutely.
莎拉
Sara...
迈克尔
Michael?
Michael.
我没事
I'm okay.
你们扶他上车
You got him to the car.
你要带他去哪
Where you gonna take him?
医院
Hospital.
好了  大家不要慌  好吗
Come on, guys, let's not freak out, all right?
-冷静点  -这是我的决定
Calm down. This is my decision,
不是你的  我们要去医院
and not yours, and we're going to the hospital.
他怎么了
Well, what's wrong with him?
大卫・贝克
David Baker.
我去  我会找出他
I'll go. I'll find him.
听着  在医院记得用假证件
Listen, don't forget to use your fake ID at the hospital, though.
-关门  -好吧
Shut the door. Okay.
怀特先生
Mr. White?
请恕我多事
If you'd allow me to be nosy,
翠珊来公司多久了
how long has Trishanne been part of the organization?
在你来之前一周
Temp agency sent her over
由短期工中介推荐过来的
about a week before you got here.
如果你不介意  我想看看
If you don't mind, I'd like to take a look
她的申请表
at her application.
在让别人处理我的私务前
I always make a point of checking out the background
我总习惯了解该人的背景
of anyone who deals with my personal affairs.
我明白
I understand.
-我会和人事部说的  -谢谢
I'll talk to HR. Thank you.
科尔
Hey, uh, Cole, you know what?
今天中午时分
Um, today around noon,
我希望你
I really need you
接替安德鲁・布劳努
to step in for Andrew Blauner.
主持一个推介会
Host an intro.
我们要征服
New franchises from Idaho.
爱荷华来的新经销商
We got to knock 'em out.
我想见识一下科尔・普发的魔法
I'd like to see some of that Cole Pfeiffer magic.
魔咒
Abracadabra.
打扰下  先生
Excuse me, sir?
你是业务员吗
Are you a salesman?
是的  我是
Yes, indeedy I am.
有什么可以为您效劳的
What can I do for you?
我知道你很忙
Well, I can see that you're busy,
但我想让你早点知道
but I didn't want you to be the last to know.
"锡拉"要转移了
Scylla is moving.
移回来吗
Come back?
别担心  我们按原计划行事
Don't worry. We're gonna stick to our original plan.
计划到底是什么
What exactly is the plan?
我们等
We wait.
-等  -没错
Wait? Yes.
你听过手抓鱼吗
Okay, have you ever heard of noodling?
没听过
I don't believe so.
你还真是个乡巴佬
Well, then, what kind of hillbilly are you, really?
我说给你听吧
I'll explain it to you.
手抓鱼
Noodling...
就是一个有勇无谋的莽夫
is when a foolhardy bastard swims
游到泥泞的河床
to the bottom of a muddy riverbed
把他的手伸到
and he sticks his hand down into the deepest,
黑暗无底的洞里
darkest hole.
抓大鲶鱼
He's looking for a prize catfish.
有时  的确有鲶鱼在洞里
Now, sometimes the catfish does live there,
抓鱼者就光着手
and the noodler pulls it out
把鱼拽出来  然后拖回岸边
with his bare hand and he drags it ashore,
但有时候  他把手伸进洞里
but sometimes, he reaches in that hole
却发现里面是啮龟
and he finds a snapping turtle.
直接把他的手咬掉了
Bites his hand clean off.
斯科菲尔德正是抓鱼者
Scofield's a noodler.
没错  如果他
Yes, and if he reaches
潜入"公司"并拿到"锡拉"
into the Company hole and he finds Scylla,
我们把它夺过来  卖给冯
we take it and we sell it to Feng.
如果他抓到啮龟
If he gets a turtle, well...
断的也不是我们的手
Not our hand.
承包商来了
The contractors are here.
你来这里干嘛
What the hell are you doing here?
我是客户
I'm a client.
你是客户吗
You're a client, huh?
冷静  大家冷静
Just keep it down; keep it down.
这是策略之一
It's all part of the ruse.
-我们需要帮助  -我时刻准备
We need some help. I'm already
提供白领风范的服务  好吧
providing my services, white-collar style, all right?
小白脸和死胖子在哪
Where's, where's Pretty and the Fatman?
贝里克死了
Bellick's dead.
你再拿这开玩笑  我就把你的舌头挖出来
If you joke about it, I'll rip your tongue out.
林肯  我们走
Let's go, Linc.
很抱歉打扰你
Sorry to bother you,
我是一名内科医生  我带我丈夫来就诊
but I'm an internist and I brought my husband in.
他刚刚晕倒了
He's in and out of consciousness
并且有一些症状令我担忧
and he's got some symptoms that concern me.
如果能见神经专科医生  我感激不尽
I'd be really grateful if we could see a neurologist.
他有人身保险吗
Does he have insurance?
有的
Uh, yeah.
我没把卡带来
I don't have the card,
但是
but, um,
我带了他的身份证
I have his I.D.
先把这个填好
Just fill this out.
好的  谢谢你
Okay, thank you.
弗里林先生
Mr. Freling?
Mr. Freling.
是  是我
Yes, that's... that's me.
一直这样吗
Is it always low?
有点
A little.
家里曾经有人患过
Has anyone in your family ever suffered
癫痫  中风  短暂性脑缺血发作等神经错乱问题吗
from epilepsy, stroke, TIAs, any neurological disorder?
我妈
My mom.
好的
Okay.
吉米  带这位先生到4号病房
Jimmy, take this gentleman back to bay four.
为什么要转移锡拉
Why are we relocating?
"锡拉"的安全事关
The Scylla's security is the foundation
整个组织
of this entire organization.
我知道
I realize that,
但你考虑过后果吗
but have you thought about the ramifications?
如果我们错失关键时机
If we lose critical access,
会延迟第二阶段的预期时间
it could compromise our timeline on stage two.
图版和设施都已齐全
The plates and the facility are ready
随时可印制任何数量的货币
to print as much currency as we need at any time.
"锡拉"何时能在宾洲安置妥当
When will Scylla be installed in Pennsylvania?
丽莎  预期时间是多少
Lisa, what's our timeline?
实际上  出了点小问题
Actually, there's been a bit of a problem.
拆除锡拉周边的
Dismantling the security
安全装置有点棘手
surrounding Scylla is a bit tricky.
可能比预期要长一点
It may take longer than we thought.
多长时间
How much longer?
我能现在就叫人拆除
I can make this happen right now.
将军有何吩咐
Yes,sir?
把大卫・贝克找来
Go get David Baker.
遵命
Yes,sir!
谁
Yes?
你好  我是来找大卫・贝克先生的
Uh, hello, I'm, uh, I'm looking for a Mr. David Baker.
他现在不接新项目了
He's not taking any new projects right now.
实际上  我想问一些他几年前
Actually, I had some... some questions about something
做的项目的事
that he worked on a few years ago.
你有听过"锡拉"的工程吗
Are you familiar with a project called Scylla?
我正忙呢
I'm working!
这位先生想跟你谈谈"锡拉"
This man would like to talk to you about Scylla.
你是"公司"的人吗
You're Company?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
我是后勤的  我想请教一些
I'm in logistics, and I'd like to ask you some questions
有关原始设计的问题
about your original design.
我想了很久才设计出来的
It's been a long time since I thought about that.
幸亏还记得一些
Be lucky to remember anything.
看来你挺忙的
Looks like you're pretty busy.
介意我看一下吗
Do you mind if I take a look?
知道吗  贝里克救过我
You know, Bellick saved my life.
什么
What?
我们在巴拿马监狱时
Back when we were in prison in Panama.
帝博格简直疯了  他是个疯子
T-Bag went crazy, he, he went nuts.
发生什么了
What happened?
他把索纳一把火烧了  把全部人都放了
He lit Sona on fire, told everyone to run.
他说  他们不会杀光我们的
They can't shoot us all, he said.
简直乱成一团  老兄  我
It was a stampede, bro, I...
我摔倒了  被人踩踏
I was down getting trampled.
站不起来
I, I couldn't get up,
无法呼吸  我以为我死定了
I couldn't breathe, I thought I was going to die...
然后有人把我拉起来
but then something pulled me back to my feet.
是贝里克
It was Bellick.
他救了我
He saved my life.
要弄倒这堵墙吗
That wall's got to come down?!
除非你有更好的办法
Unless you got a better idea.
好吧
Okay.
什么东西
What was that?
不知道  我好像踩到什么了
I don't know. I think I stepped on something.
怎么回事  林肯
What's going on, Linc?
我不知道  老兄
I don't know, man.
像是某种引爆装置
It's some kind of explosive.
炸弹  那我不是死定了
Explosive? Then shouldn't I be dead?
你要是乱动的话  就死定了
If you move, you'll be.
他们在地下  你打不通的
They're underground, you're not going to be able to reach them.
对
Right.
你知道吗
You know what?
没有你  他们也行的
They'll be fine without you.
对
Right.
你听说过福克斯河监狱吗
You ever heard of Fox River?
或许我们可以边吃晚饭边聊聊
Maybe we could talk about it over dinner.
我有洲际公路边上的红虾海鲜馆的优惠卡
I got a gift card to the Red Lobster over off the interstate.
我没想到他们会为布拉德・贝里克这么伤心
I never thought the guys would be so sad for Brad Bellick.
在福克斯河监狱  很多事情都变了
A lot of things have changed since Fox River.
你要知道你掌控不了这些
You know you can't control this.
真的
Yeah?
真有趣  我刚想跟你说同样的话
It's funny, I was just about to tell you the same thing.
不管如何  我们都能应对
Whatever it is, we can manage it.
只要知道我们要应对的是什么
We just need to know what we're dealing with.
如果我不想知道呢
What if I don't want to know?
凯文・弗里林
Kevin Freling
只需几分钟而已
Should only take a few minutes.
准备好了吗
You ready?
好了
I'm ready.
我的目标是建立一个完全自给的城市
My goal is to build one city that entirely self-sustains,
不依靠任何外部资源
depending on no outside resources.
一个完全和谐的社会
A community living entirely in harmony.
还需多久才能转变成现实
How close is it to becoming a reality?
这得看舆论反应了
Well, that's a matter of opinion.
人们认为这些
People look at something
都是不可能的
like this and they think it's impossible.
在现实中  我第二天就能实现这个设想
In reality, I could make it happen tomorrow.
正如他们在迪拜所建设的
Like what they built in Dubai.
没错  把伟大设想
Exactly-- grand ideas
转变成现实
brought into reality.
这不仅只是有益于富人
This won't just serve the rich.
你为他们工作多久了
How long have you been working for them?
太久了
Too long.
94年加入的
I came in in '94.
我从不习惯固定工资
I was never good at collecting a paycheck.
一直是自由职业
Always freelance.
基本上不断辞职
Partially retired all the time.
我喜欢完成一项工作后就往前发展
I like to finish a job and then move on.
把完成的事置于脑后
Put it in the past.
你总是只留名字
Do you always leave your name behind,
而不留正确的工程细则吗
instead of the correct specifications?
只在"锡拉"工程如此而已
Only on the Scylla project.
我们正在考虑修改方案
Well, we're considering modifications and...
我希望你能
I was hoping that you...
帮我指明
could help me figure out
那些蓝图上确切指的是什么
what should really appear on those blueprints.
因为  现在看不出多少意义
As of right now, they don't mean much.
你看了图标符号吗
Didn't you read the legend?
当然
Sure.
但我们还有很多麻烦
But we still had a lot of trouble.
你不是"公司"的人
You're not Company.
我该怎么办
What should I do?
保持冷静
Stay calm.
怎么冷静  你说我踩上地雷了
Calm?! You just said I'm standing on a bomb!
我们会有办法的
We'll work it out.
难道是格雷琴陷害我们
You think Gretchen set us up?
由公司的
"The lessons
创始人哈维・霍尔先生
taught by our founder, Mister..."
传授的课程
"...Harvey Hall."
通向个人自由的路径
"Pathway to personal freedom."
那些人会听这些废话吗
Do people actually buy this nonsense?
放开我
Let go of me.
要么跟我来  要么把你从玻璃门砸过去
You're coming with me or through that glass.
选吧
Choose.
这可是办公地点
This is a place of business.
伽特帮我们找到通向
GATE allows us to find the pathway
个人自由的路径
to personal freedom.
定义我们的范围
Define our boundaries.
并且超出范围考虑
See past them.
让我告诉你们这项伟大工程的
Let me tell you a story about the founder
创始人的故事
of this great program.
我还是给你们讲比这个俗套的老故事
You know, I'm gonna tell you a better story
更棒的故事  有关被囚禁的故事
about captivity than the regular old spiel.
几年前
Years back,
我在一个当地重罪监狱
I was providing volunteer leadership
当志愿者领导
in a local penitentiary.
我和一个壮硕魁梧又弓形腿的
I worked with the head guard,
守卫队长布拉德共事
a big, burly, bowlegged Brad.
和恶魔一样可恶
Mean as the devil.
所有罪犯都很怕他  甚至是谋杀犯
All the prisoners were afraid of him, even the murderers.
有一天  布拉德对我说
And one day, Brad said to me,
科尔  我要你离开这里
"Cole, I want you to get out of here.
我要你立刻离开这里
"I want you to get out of here right now,
因为我知道你是个热爱自由的人
'cause I can tell you're a man who loves freedom."
我说  布拉德  那你呢
And I said, "Well, what about you, Brad?
你呢
What about you?"
他说  我嘛
He said, "Oh, yeah, I'm... I'm...
退休时我就自由了
I'm gonna be free someday when I retire."
最近我得知他去世了
I recently got the news that he had passed away.
他在哪过世的呢
And where was he?
还在那个监狱
Still in that prison.
仍然囚禁在充满消极思想的监狱里
Still in the captivity of negativity.
抱歉  各位
Sorry, folks.
老布拉德
Old Brad.
正如我老爸所说的
As my papa used to say,
站直  拿稳酒杯
"Stand by, your glasses steady,
为你的战友干杯
"and drink to your comrade's eyes.
向已故的人致敬
"Here's a toast to the dead already,
为后继的人欢呼
and hurrah for the next to die."
为了确保
I needed to make sure
我能拿到你的诊断结果
that I would have access to your test results,
我跟分拣护士说
so I told the triage nurse
我是你的妻子
that I was your wife.
说得真有一套
Has a nice ring.
你是凯文・弗里林吗
Are you Kevin Freling?
我是
Yes, I am.
我是摩尔登医生
I'm Dr. Malden.
我是神经专科医生  你是
I'm a neurologist. And you're...
我是卡梅伦・艾勃兰  我是一名内科医生
Cameron Eberline. I'm a... an internist.
有结果了吗
Do you have the results?
还要等一会
It's gonna take a little while.
通过家族病史
Uh, looking at the family history,
我想让你留院观察
I'd like to admit you here.
我们在安排病房
We're working on a room.
就现在
Just for now,
直到拿到检查报告
until we get the test results back.
我觉得没必要  但还是谢谢你
I don't think that'll be necessary, but thank you.
你最好能在
It would be best if you could rest
有看护的地方休息
where you could be monitored.
之后  我们再决定
After that, we'll determine
最佳治疗方案
what the best course of action is.
同意吗
Agreed?
抱歉  我们得走了
I think we have to go. I'm sorry.
等等  多长时间
Hold on, hold on-- how long... how long will it take
-能拿到结果  -几小时
to get the results? Couple of hours.
期间我们会给你安排一间病房
But we'll get you in a room before then.
-在这稍等  -谢谢
Just wait here. Thank you.
过来吧
Come on.
你知道会怎样吗
You know what happens?
他们会控制你的生活
They take over your life.
你没法自己掌控
You don't own it anymore.
事情不像你说的那样
That is not what happened to me.
不管怎样  你过去没惹上麻烦
Then, somehow you stayed out of trouble.
你按他们说的做了
You did what they told you to do.
这正是你被困在这的原因  对吧
Maybe that's why you stuck around, huh?
困在洛杉机
Right here in Los Angeles.
而我  他们抓到我的把柄
In my case, they had something on me,
他们利用这点穷追不舍
and they used it and they never let me go.
他们杀人无数
They've killed hundreds, thousands of people
谋权求势  你一清二楚
in the pursuit of power, you know that.
我们昨天就牺牲了一名想阻止他们的同志
We lost a good man yesterday trying to stop them.
他们伤害了太多人  大卫
They hurt a lot of people, David.
大卫
David.
听着
Look...
我不参与政治
I stay out of the politics.
那只是份工作
It was a job.
我专门负责安全工程
I specialized in security engineering.
"锡拉"工程只是个选择性的任务  所以我就接受了
The Scylla project was a choice assignment, so I took it.
他们告诉你那是什么了  对吧
They told you what it was, didn't they?
他们跟你说了它  如今
They told you what it was, and now
你希望你从没帮过他们  但你被骗了
you wish that you never helped them, but you're trapped.
正如我被陷害一样
You're trapped like I was.
你说得好像就在眼前的事
You talk like it's all in the present.
确实如此
It is!
我知道你想忘掉过去
I know you want to move on.
看看你在做什么
Look at what you're doing.
你在努力弥补吧
Are you trying to make up for something?
忘了美好的未来吧
Forget the charitable city of the future,
还是关心一下你眼前的生活吧  大卫
and worry about the world that you live in right now, David.
他们做过的  他们要做的
What they did.what they're doing.
都不是我的错
is not my fault.
你把名字留在那里肯定有原因
You put your name in there for a reason.
你想让人找到你
You wanted someone to find you,
如果你说出我想要的信息
and if you tell me what I need to know,
我能为彼此做出努力
I can do something for both of us.
你丈夫在哪
Where is your husband?
他出去办公了  一会才能回来
He went to run some errands-- he should be right back.
车道停的不是他的车吗
That's his car in the driveway, isn't it?
稍等  我打电话叫他
Just a moment. I'll call him on his cell.
-你们干嘛  -要求派人前后包抄
Excuse me.I request southeast to work.
你早就知道  对吧
You knew about this, didn't you?
首先  我不知道
First of all, I have no idea
"公司"为何
why the Company would want
在自己楼下
to put an explosive device
放何种爆炸装置
of any kind under their own building.
-我们在中庭下方  -告诉你
We're under the courtyard. And you know what,
我完全不知情
I honestly had no idea
这里会有这些东西
that any of this was even here.
这么看来
That being said...
这看起来像JZ33杀伤性地雷
These look a lot like JZ33 anti-personnel blast mines.
过去  在费卢杰
Back in Fallujah,
伊斯兰游击战士把它们埋在基地外面
the Muj used to bury them outside their firm base.
除掉他们
Get rid of them.
我不是专家  但我有主意
I'm no expert, but I have an idea.
什么在哔哔叫
What's beeping?
哔哔声啊
It beeps!
你肯定直接踩到上面
Wow, you must've stepped on this just right.
你的重心平均
Your weight is evenly distributed
分布在压板上
across the pressure plate,
没有触动引线
and you haven't engaged the firing pin.
一英寸你都不能挪
You can't move an inch.
我们知道
We know.
你有什么主意
What's your idea?
我的想法是他挪一英寸
Well, my idea is that he moves an inch.
这样  我就能深入洞里
That way, I can get to the hole,
拆除引线
and I can dismantle the firing pin.
他现在站在上面  我无能为力
Right now, he's standing on it, and I can't do anything.
不行  林肯  打电话给你弟弟[西班牙语]
No, no, no, Linc,  llama tu hermano.
-什么  -快打电话给你弟弟
What? Call your brother, please.
你给我呆在这里
You-- you stay here.
行
Fine.
是我哥哥
It's my brother.
迈克尔
Michael...
我们走
Let's go.
莎拉
Sara...
你们不是要走吧
You're not leaving, are you?
你有我们的号码
You have our number.
你到底是谁
And who are you again?
他想在家等结果
He prefers to wait at home.
-我会照看他  -他可能有危险
I'm monitoring him. He's leaving AMA
不能离开医院
in a potentially fragile condition.
听着  我不是傻瓜
Look, I'm not stupid.
我知道你们是谁
I know who you are,
我不会告发你们
and I'm not gonna turn you in.
我关心的是
My concern is for what's going on
你的健康
with your health.
他们不是来抓你们的
They aren't here for you,
我告诉你  以你的状况
and I'm telling you, in your condition...
谢谢你医生  我很感激你帮忙
Thank you, Doctor; I appreciate your help.
拜托打电话给我们
Please do call us.
有事吗
Can I help you?
我搞砸了
I messed up.
什么意思
What do you mean?
今天  我跟巴格维尔一起办事时
Today, I was working with Bagwell.
他很顺从
He's been compliant as hell.
我想我可以让他高兴
I thought that I would make him happy.
-他想谈论格雷琴・摩根  -行  到底怎么了
He wanted to talk about Gretchen Morgan. Right, and what happened?
而我说漏嘴了
And I slipped up.
我提到惠斯勒了
I mentioned Whistler.
我告诉你这很棘手
This one is tough, I'm telling you.
巴格维尔  格雷琴・摩根  他们很凶残
Bagwell, Gretchen Morgan-- they're thugs.
我不止一次被人
I have been face down with a gun
拿枪指着我的头
to the back of my head more than once.
好吧
All right.
听着  我不想让你去做
Look, I don't want you to do something
你不想做的事情
that you don't want to do.
你是个好特工  我们可以安排其他人
You're a good agent-- we could reassign...
不  我不是这个意思
No, no, that is not it.
听着  我能搞掂这个
Look, I can handle this.
我只是
I'm just...
我只是在鞭策自己
I'm just kicking myself.
我可以安排其他事给你做
I could find something else for you to do, okay?
这件事你就别管了
This thing has gotten way out of hand.
达洛在后方  并且"公司"正在转移"锡拉"
Dallow is on my back, and the Company is moving Scylla...
不
No.
我能行
I'm fine.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
唐  我真的觉得我们能行
I really think we can do this, Don.
我们能搞垮"公司"
We can bring the Company down.
我把名字记在蓝图上完全是自负
Ego is the only reason I coded my name into those blueprints.
我不觉得有什么好心虚的
I don't feel guilty about anything.
我得接这个电话  不好意思
I gotta take this. I'm sorry.
喂
Hello?
-阿历克斯 我们  -怎么了
Alex, we...What?
有麻烦了
Got a problem.
那里有个该死的雷区
There's a damn minefield down there.
喂  我听不清
Hello, I can't hear you.
苏克雷有麻烦了
Sucre's in trouble.
他踩到地雷了
He's standing on a mine.
我们得把它拆了
We need to deactivate it.
林肯  我得挂了  一会打给你
Linc, I gotta go. I'll call you back.
他们来了  大卫
They're here, David.
-他们想从我这要什么  -他们在转移"锡拉"
What do they want from me? They're moving Scylla,
保护它  所有你为他们做的
protecting it-- everything you did for them,
他们想让你再做一次
they want you to do it again.
你觉得你能阻止他们吗
You think you can stop them?
我了解你
I know all about you.
我六个月前就知道了
I've known about you for six months.
自从有人从公司偷了
ever since somebody stole those plans
设计图
from the Company.
一切都是徒劳
It will never work.
你们连第一堵墙都过不去
You won't get past the first wall.
第一堵墙指什么
What about the first wall?
有什么障碍  雷区吗
What's gonna stop me, huh? The minefield?
千万别告诉他们
Please... don't tell 'em.
我们抓到他了  清理现场
We've got him. Sweep the area.
山脚下有条泥路
There's a dirt road at the bottom of the hill.
从那条路出去
It will take you out.
-你丈夫  -只管走
Your husband... Just go.
他帮不了你  这个东西可以
He won't help you; that will.
"锡拉"工程
Scylla Project
林肯  再给他打电话
Lincoln, go call him again.
林肯  快打啊
Linc, go call him.
快啊  林肯
Linc, go call him!
迈克尔知道怎么处理吗
What will Michael know about this?
这完全超出他的知识领域
I mean, it's not exactly within his realm of expertise.
我们这是浪费时间
We're wasting time.
我给的是半专业化建议
I gave you a semiprofessional assessment.
那又如何
What's wrong?
你不相信我吗  费尔南多
You don't trust me, Fernando?
他为何要相信你
Why should he?
因为我们的目标一致  "锡拉"
Because we all want the same thing: Scylla.
我不会让一大包爆竹
And I'm not gonna let a giant pack
挡我们的路
of firecrackers stand in our way.
要不我给你找个拆弹小组
Or would you like me to call the bomb squad?
听着  我现在是好心相助
Look, I am offering to do you a massive favor here.
我拆引线时  这东西要是炸了
If that thing blows while I'm pulling the pin,
他丢的是一条腿  我丢的可是头
he loses a leg-- I lose a face!
费尔南多  别担心
Now, don't worry, Fernando.
我出了名手稳
I'm known for my steady hand.
深呼吸  好吧
Take a deep breath, okay?
保持重心平稳
Keep your weight even.
然后慢慢移动
And I need you to shift slowly,
慢慢的
very slowly--
往左挪一英寸  我就能拆引线了
one inch to your left, so I can get to the pin.
不行  我做不到
Oh, no, I can't... I can't, I can't do it.
你还好吧
Are you all right?
有什么消息吗
Have you, uh, heard anything?
他们得拆除它
They have to deactivate.
我拿到张图表
I got a key.
蓝图中的图标符号
A legend to the blueprint.
-贝克给你的吗  -不是
Baker gave you this? No.
他老婆给我的  他们找上贝克了
His wife gave it to me. They came for Baker.
好了  这样就清楚多了
All right, well, this makes more sense.
这些符号
These, uh, these symbols
不是代表P型管  代表的是
aren't for p-traps, they're...
麦克风
they're microphones.
字母V代表真空装置
And the letter "V" isn't for vacuum,
那是发电机
that's a generator.
这是一条JZ33的布雷线
This is a line of JZ33 land mines
埋在地下8毫米处
buried 80 millimeters underground,
离外墙大概有7英尺
about seven feet from the outer wall
肯定是林肯和我说的事
that's must be what Linc was talking about.
上面说  只能手动操作
It says, "Manual override only.
所有常规拆除JZ33的方式
All conventional attempts to dismantle the JZ33
均会触发"锡拉"警报
will activate the Scylla alarms."
这不仅仅是个地雷
This isn't just a land mine.
还是个报警器
This is, uh... this is an alarm.
我们不能耗一个晚上
We can't sit here all night.
准备好了吗
Okey?You ready?
我是林肯  你知道怎么做
it's Linc. You know what to do.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
林肯
Linc!
苏克雷
Sucre!
住手
Stop!
快住手
别动
Don't move.
千万别的
不关掉警报
You can't dismantle the land mine
-你是拆不了地雷的  -也就是说
without setting off the alarm. So I either
不但关不了警报
set off the alarm
-我还会被炸死  -不
or blow up and die. No.
有一个手动装置
There's a manual override.
切断电源后有足够时间
It'll cut the power long enough for you
让你不拆引线退后
to step off without removing the pin.
你怎么肯定吗
How do you know for sure?
我找到大卫・贝克了
I found David Baker.
苏克雷  退后
Sucre. Step off.
你可以的
You can do it. You only have
你只有20秒时间  快点
20 seconds. Come on.
-我做不到  -你可以的
I can't... Yes, you can. Yes, you can.
我和迈克尔研究过了
Michael and I figured it out.
现在就退后
Step off right now.
不  你们都走吧  我
No, no, you guys all go. I'll--
我们不必都死  我自己承担吧
We all don't have to die. I'll do it alone.
今天没有人会死
Nobody's gonna die today!
退后
Step off!
Step off.
墙后面是什么
What's behind this wall?
锡拉
Scylla.
你们什么时候能知道结果
When do you find out?
医生随时都有可能打电话来
The doctor is supposed to call, uh... any minute.
听着
Look, um...
我很抱歉今天没去帮你们
I'm sorry I wasn't there for you today.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
格雷琴为苏克雷所做的
You know, what Gretchen did for Sucre
让我觉得我们可以信任她
made me realize we could use her.
我问她要第六张卡
I asked for the sixth key.
她怎么说
What'd she say?
她在努力
She's on it.
你没事吧
You all right?
好了
All right.
我们准备去机场
We're about to go to the airfield.
把布拉德的尸体运给他母亲
We're gonna ship Brad's body off to his mother.
他的遗物都在这
Got his things here.
他在哪
Where is he?
这边
Over here.
他妈妈会为此感激的
His mother will appreciate that.
贝里克夫人
Mrs. Bellick.
我是费尔南多・苏克雷
This is Fernando Sucre.
今天干的不错
Great job today.
我对你朋友的死感到遗憾
I'm sorry to hear about your friend.
但那是令人尊敬的工作
But that's, um, admirable work,
志愿看管那样一群罪犯
volunteering with a bunch of criminals like that.
我们都是一样的
We're all the same, really.
这是你要的
Here's the application you requested
前台的申请表
for the desk girl.
谢谢
Thanks.
祝你晚上愉快  科尔
You have a good night, Cole.
你也是  谢谢
You, too. Thanks.
喂
Hello?
好的
Okay.
我们会的
We will.
谢谢
Thank you.
吃过一番苦头
As we've all learned the hard way,
我们已知道在地基周边
there's an electronic alarm barrier
装有电子报警设备
around the perimeter of the foundation.
不幸的是
Unfortunately,
那是锡拉最外层的防线
that is Scylla's most primitive line of defense.
那面墙
The wall itself
用钢纤维设防
is fortified with steel fiber.
好消息是  在里面
The good news is, on the inside here,
没有监控录像
there are no cameras.
公司不想留下任何
The Company doesn't want any
证明"锡拉"存在的视觉图像
visual evidence that Scylla exists.
坏消息是  这边和这边
The bad news is that there are both
都有重量和扩音传感器
weight and microphonic sensors here and here
一旦有任何超过
that will alert Company Security
2磅的活人出现
to the presence of any breathing human being
就会拉响"公司"的安全警报
that weighs more than two pounds.
我现在能确定的
as far as I can tell,
第一个挑战  是避开那堵墙
the first challenge is getting around that wall.
然后再考虑如何跨过那块地
And then we can worry about crossing the floor.
不能碰到地面
Without touching it.
还得悄无声息
In silence.
太复杂了
It's complicated.
但我已经在研究了
But, uh, I'm already working on something.
布拉德没有白白牺牲
Brad didn't die in vain.
我们会成功的
We can make this work.
神经专科医生打来的电话
That was the neurologist.
你长了个下丘脑错构瘤
You have a hypothalamus hamaratoma.
十分罕见
It's really rare.
你可能天生就有
You were probably born with it.
情况变了  肿瘤在变大
Um, things have changed-- it's been growing,
所以你会出现这些症状
which is why you've been experiencing your symptoms.
医生认为你得动手术
And the doctor feels that you need surgery.
再等两天
Two days.
我只需要两天
That's, uh, that's what I need.
不  明天就得做
No. Tomorrow.
否则你会死的  别无选择
Otherwise you could die, and there's no alternative.